# VIOLA GARCIA

211 MARGARET LN, RED OAK, TX 75154 | (214) 949-5173 | vg0988@hotmail.com

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I currently have over 25 years and extensive knowledge of Medical Billing and A/R experience, as well as, Customer Service and Office experience. UB04 Hospital claim & HCFA1500

SOFTWARE, Excel, Word, Lytec 2005 Medical Software, Medisoft V12, HBOC, Radnet/Patcom, ChartScan, Eclinical V10.0, Caremedic (Medicare software program) Meditech, EPIC.

Dedicated Accounts Receivable Specialist with [Number] years of professional experience in credit, collections and cash application. Expert in accurately posting payments via bank statements, lock box and credit cards to keep accounts current. Excited to bring talent, leadership and in-depth knowledge of accounts receivable to growing organization.

#### SKILLS

- A/R (10+ years), Medical Billing (10+ Data Entry years), EPIC. (2 years), Excel (10+ years), Excellent written (10+ years), Excellent written and verbal communication skills. (10+ years), HBOC • Invoicing proficiency (2 years), Medicare (10+ years), Medisoft (5 years), Meditech (2 years), Office experience. (10+ years), RECEPTIONIST (5 years), RETAIL SALES (4 years), Word (10+ years), written and verbal (10+ years)
- Bill processing
- Accounts Payable/ Accounts Receivable
- Credit and collections
- Billing dispute resolution

- Documentation
- Cross-functional team collaboration
  - Claims processing

## WORK HISTORY

#### AUGUST 2016-DECEMBER 2018

Accounts Receivable Specialist | Methodist Health System | Dallas, TX

- Duties Included: Accounts Receivable & Billing for hospital facility. Called insurance companies to follow-up on claim status to ensure timely filing. Contacted patients if additional information is needed, verified insurance eligibility and review EOB's on processed claims and ensure claim processed at correct contracted rate. Documented account activity. Cross trained for all payer mixes.
- Managed more than 50-60 per day, worked daily claim edits, DNB/Stop bills, denials,
   Credit balance and variances, No response claims and correspondence. Uploaded medical records daily when requested.

#### APRIL 2011-FEBRUARY 2016

Orthopedic A/R Specialist | Ellis County Medical Associates | Ennis, TX

• Duties Included: Accounts Receivable for Multi-Specialty Physicians include Orthopedic Surgeon, General & Vascular Surgery, Cardiologist, Family Practice, and Internal Medicine. Responsibilities included follow-up on Insurance Aging for all payer mixes such as Medicaid, Medicare, Workers Comp., Major Medical, Liability and Attorney accounts, as well as, submission of secondary claims. Submitted appeal letters when necessary, Corrected and resubmitted denied claims. Assisted occasionally with mail, deposits and posting of payments. Utilized medical software Eclinical Works V10.0. Managed 50 accounts per day, answered incoming patient calls and assisted with patient payment plans.

#### SEPTEMBER 2005-APRIL 2011

Accounts Receivable Specialist | Professional Billing Systems | Waxahachie, TX

Duties Included: Data entry, Accounts Receivable and medical billing for Home Health,
Radiology, Family Practice accounts. Payment posting, answer all incoming calls.
Specialized in collections for Medicare, Medicaid to ensure maximum reimbursement
and utilization of all resources available. Filed Auto, Major Medical, Workers
Compensation, Attorney claims. Transmitted electronic claims, Insurance follow-up.
Experience in credentialing Medicaid applications. Answered all incoming calls,
insurance follow-up, contacted insurance companies when necessary, data entry,
Medical Billing and Account Receivables for Radiologist, Podiatrist, Bariatric, General
Surgeon, DME, Home Health. Managed over 60 or more accounts daily.

APRIL 2007-JUNE 2008

Patient Access Specialist | Baylor Medical Center At Waxahachie & Red Oak Imaging Center | Waxahachie, TX

- Duties included: Patient check-in, Pre-registered patients, scheduled out-patient procedures, answered all incoming scheduling line, prepared packets that included patient order, insurance info, demographics, processed electronic payments, searched for patient order when necessary and called doctor's office to request for orders, additional ICD-9 or demos to verify accuracy. Requested patient orders for MRI, Mammogram, Ultrasound, Computed tomography, X-ray and Lab technicians, scanned patient insurance card and DL.
- Obtained signatures from financial responsibility and treatment procedures from patients or guardians.
- Prepared patient identification band and completed admissions papers.
- Collected and validated patient demographics and insurance information.
- Performed general office duties, including answering multi-line phones, routing telephone calls or messages to appropriate staff and greeting visitors.

### **EDUCATION**

1987

High School Diploma
Red Oak High School, Red Oak, TX